CAMILO AGUILAR

225 Sackville St | Toronto ON, M5A 0B9 | +1 (437) 985-4432 | cam1726@hotmail.com

Career Summary

I am Business administrator with more than 5 years of experience as a Business Analyst. I have worked on various IT projects for Fortune 500 companies, utilizing different methodologies such as agile and waterfall. My expertise lies in customer relationship management and payments compliance, where I have experience in both implementing and analyzing requirements and converting them into solutions. Additionally, I am skilled in defining functional and non-functional user requirements to guide teams in evaluating, planning, designing, and building a product.

Technical Skills:

- Confluence
- Jira
- User Story definition
- CMS (AEM Adobe Experience Manager)
- Web Development
- SQL
- CRM
- Mural
- Axure
- HTML

- Python
- Scrum Methodologies
- Banking Applications
- Oracle Flexcube
- Postman
- Mongo DB
- C# / .NET
- JavaScript
- GraphQL

Personal Skills:

- Proactive
- Assertive communication
- Willingness to trial
- Flexibility
- Close observation
- Collaboration

Languages:

Spanish

• English

Career History

Globant Nov 2021 - Jan 2023

Business Analyst Ssr

Responsible for identifying and gathering business requirements and turning them into a simple and refined clean solution by figuring out why users need a new application or enhancement and then defining functional, non-functional and user requirements that teams can use to assess, plan, design and build a product, based on scrum methodology using tools like Jira to write and refine user stories.

Main Responsibilities:

- Gathering requirement and documenting them in confluence
- Make flowcharts with various tools to understand the processes that are required in order to transmit them with the development team.
- Create user stories in Jira and keep them updated and refined.
- Participate and lead scrum ceremonies.
- Maintain the understanding of the entire team regarding the user's requirements, creating participatory sessions.

Tata Consultancy Services, Technical Implementation Manager

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2021

Global Consultant to Citibank. Responsible for Citibank product implementations for Global Clients. Responsible for the relationship between the Clients and the Bank, performing successful implementations using management tools as CRM- JIRA, analyzing payments/ transactions/ remittances for OSFI compliance in different formats like XML, IDOC, CP2E, Flat files etc. working together with different stakeholders either from Citibank or with teams directly from the client, managing projects related to time, reporting, deliverables, with assertive and efficient communication with global clients.

Main Responsibilities:

- Use CRM Customer relationship management system to keep track of all my clients.
- Lead follow-up meetings, confirmation of the scope of the project, as well as manage project deliverable times.
- Gathering documentation using confluence
- Offer the right solution to customers according to their needs.
- Implement server-to-server connectivity's as AS2 FTP SFTP / PGP file encryptions, ETC.
- Guide and walkthrough to global clients in the use of payment files such as XML, IDOC, CP2E, Flat files etc.
- Extracted Tracking and compliance monitoring files for payments like SWIFT using DataStage.

Tata Consultancy Services, IT ANALYST

July. 2018 - Dec. 2019

As a Global Consultant for Citibank at Tata Consultancy Services, I specialized in Oracle Flexcube implementations for important global banking clients in Latin America. My tasks included:

- Gathering specific client requirements
- Designing and building Banking Service Modules (BSMs)
- Providing skill training to improve team effectiveness and application utilization
- Creating execution process documentation using Agile tools like JIRA
- Reviewing end-to-end testing of Flexcube transactions
- Developing functional test cases
- Addressing team inquiries related to banking application functionality
- Participating in project ceremonies for progress monitoring
- Through my contributions, the implementation process was streamlined, ensuring successful integration of Flexcube into the banking operations of clients in Latin America

Tata Consultancy Services, HR Compensation and Benefits – (Intern)

Database management of employee's information in different locations. Oversaw changes in roles, income, withdrawals and benefits. Vendor Management of contracts with suppliers, including review of billing and employee concerns related to benefits. Calculate and assign Travel Allowance for national and international Trips.

- Vendor management
- Billing and employee concerns
- analysis of Benefits
- Database management

Education

Centennial College, Canada, Toronto, ON
Post Graduate degree in SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2023 - Till Date

Universidad de San Buenaventura, Bogotá, Colombia BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

July. 2014 – Dec. 2019